Guide to the Reference Center for Marxist Studies Pamphlet Collection PE.043
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Germany: World War II (11 pamphlets) (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Pieck, Wilhelm. International Solidarity. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1941 (Box 41, Folder 5)
- Ghana (10 pamphlets) (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - African Cultural Renaissance. The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, Accra, Ghana., 1964 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Guide to Party Action. The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, Accra, Ghana., 1962 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Kwame Nkrumah and the African Revolution. The Spark Publication, Accra, Ghana., 1964 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Nkrumah, Kwame. The Spectre of Black of Power. Panaf Publications Limited, London., undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Peace! The World From African Eyes. Afro-American Heritage Ass'n, Chicago, IL. (2 copies), 1960 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Prospectus. Kwame Nkrumah Ideological Institute, Winneba, Ghana., undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - State Opening of Parliament. The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, Accra, Ghana., 1963 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - The African Genius. The Ministry of Information and Broadcastin, Accra, Ghana., 1963 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Towards Socialism. The Ministry of Information and Broadcasting, Accra, Ghana., 1962 (Box 41, Folder 6)
- Gold, Ben (contains an article) (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Ben Gold dies in Fla., founder of fur union. Daily World., 1985 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Funeral for Ben Gold, fur-leather union leader. Daily World., 1985 (Box 41, Folder 7)
- Goldwater, Barry (2 pamphlets) (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Newberry, Mike. Goldwaterism. Marzani and Munsell, New York, NY. (2 copies), 1964 (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Gorbachev Period (1 pamphlet and a report) (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Gorbachev, Mikhail. On the Tasks of the Party in the Radical Restructuring of Economic Management. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow., 1987 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Hall, Gus. Assessments of Developments in the Soviet Union, 1987-1991. Political Affairs., undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
- Gorky, Maxim (7 pamphlets and an article) (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Gorky, Maxim. To American Intellectuals. International Pamphlets, New York, NY. (3 copies), 1932 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Gorky, Maxim. V.I. Lenin. Novosti Press Agency Publishing House, Moscow. (2 copies), 1973 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Yermilov, Vladimir. Gorky - Staunch Fighter Against Fascism. Mezhdunarodnaya Kniga (International Book), Moscow., 1941 (Box 42, Folder 2)
- Great Britain I (9 pamphlets) (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Bradley, Ben. The Colonies and the Future. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Hallas, Duncan. The Meaning of Marxism. International Socialist, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Lauchlan, William. Searchlight on the Tories. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Lewis, John. Marxism and Modern Idealism. Lawrence & Wishart Ltd, London., 1944 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Lindsay, Jack. England, My England... Fore Publications Ltd., London., undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - London Landmarks: A Guide with Maps to Places Where Marx, Engels and Lenin Lived and Worked. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Mortishead, R. J. P. Problems of International Organisation: An Outline for Study Circles. Workers Educational Association and Workers Educational Trade Union Committee, London., 1944 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - "One Happy Family": The Plain Man's Guide to the Coronation. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - The British Empire. League Against Imperialism and for National Independence, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - The Colonies: The Way Forward. Executive Committee of the Communist Party, London., 1944 (Box 42, Folder 3)
- Great Britain II (11 pamphlets) (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Dobb, Maurice. Economics of Capitalism. People's Publishing House, Bombay., undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Dobb, Maurice. Economics of Private Enterprise: An Introductory Outline. Current Book Distributors, Sydney., 1944 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - For Unity in London. Communist Party, London., 1938 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Greenwood, Jennifer. Music for the Club. Workers' Music Association, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Heinemann, Margot. The Tories and how to beat them. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Montagu, Ivor. The Federal Union Myth. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Morton, A.L. When the People Arose: The Peasants Revolt of 1381. The Communist Party of Great Britain, London. (2 copies), 1981 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - People's Theatre. Progress Publishing Co, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Reid, Betty. Ultra Leftism in Britain. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Zilliacus, K. Our Lives and Cuba...What Britain Must Do to Survive. New Gladiator Pamphlet Club, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
- Great Britain: Atomic Power (3 pamphlets) (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Atomic Attack: Can Britain Be Defended? Association of Scientific Workers, London., 1950 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Blackett, P.M.S. The Atom and the Charter. Fabian Society, London., 1946 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Paul, William. Atomic Energy and Social Progress. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
- Great Britain: CP I (21 pamphlets) (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Falber, Reuben. How Will You Vote. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Handbook for the members of the Communist Party. Communist Party of Great Britain., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Handbook on Local Organisation. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1927 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Hart, Finlay. The Communist Party and the Trade Unions. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Improve our Party Organisation. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Kartun, Derek. America - Go Home! The Communist Party, London., 1951 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Kerrigan, Peter. The Communist Party. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Lauchlan, William. The Communist Party. The Communist Party, London., 1949 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Organising for Victory in 1943. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Organising to win the Offensive. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Party Organisation and the Invasion. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Party Organisation and the Offensive. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Reid, Betty. Ultra Leftism in Britain. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Report of the Executive Committee to 18th Party Congress. The Communist Party, London., 1945 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Robson, R. W. Essentials of Communist Theory. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Speed the Campaign. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - The Communist Party and the role of the branches. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - The Communist Party: Its Theory and Practice. Central Books, Ltd., London. (2 copies), undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - The Role of the Communist Party. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Tune up our organisation. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Woods, Charlie. The Crisis in Our Communist Party - Cause, Effect, and Cure. C.R. Woods, Westerhope., undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
- Great Britain: CP II (13 pamphlets) (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Changing Britain: The need for the Communist Party. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Communism: An Outline for Everyone. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Constitution and Rules. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1921 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Discussion Notes: Why you became a Communist. Communist Party, London., 1943 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Gollan, John. Which Way for Socialists? The Case for the Communist Party. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - How I joined the Communist Party. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1942 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - How to Defend Yourself: A Practical Legal Guide for Workers. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1940 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - How to organise Public Meetings. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1942 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Kartun, Derek. Freedom & the Communists. The Communist Party, London., 1955 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Local Election Facts For Speakers and Canvassers. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - The British Road to Socialism. The Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - The Case for the New Communist Party. New Communist Party, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - The Crisis in the Communist Party and the Way Forward. Communist Campaign Group., undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Wainwright, W. Why you should be a communist. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
- Great Britain: Daily Worker (10 pamphlets) (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Citrine & others v Pountney: The Daily Worker Libel Case. Modern Books, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Daily Worker Debate: The Speech of W. Gallacher, M.P. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1941 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Daily Worker in the Fight for Victory: Report of Delegate Conference. The Daily Worker League, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Hands Off the Daily Worker. Daily Worker, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Rust, William. Daily Worker Reborn. The Daily Worker League, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Rust, William. Gagged by Grigg. Daily Worker League, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Rust, William. It's Your Paper: The Story of the Eleventh Year of the "Daily Worker." The Daily Worker, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Rust, William. The Inside Story of the Daily Workers: 10 Years of Working Class Journalism. Daily Worker Readers' League, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - The Case for the Daily Worker. Daily Worker, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - The Daily Worker and The War: A reprint of thirty selected articles from June 15, 1940 up to January 21, 1941. Daily Worker Defence League, London., undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
- Great Britain: Education (6 pamphlets) (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Britain's Schools. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Bramley, Ted. Communism and Education. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Education: Communist Party Policy. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Gollan, W.E. Education in Crisis and the Way Forward. Current Book Distributors, Sydney., 1959 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Wiles, Maurice. A New Deal For Our Children. Communist Party, London. (2 copies), 1962 (Box 43, Folder 1)
- Great Britain: Fascism (8 pamphlets) (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Fascism: Fight It Now. Labour Research Department, London., 1937 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Fascists at Olympia: A Record of Eye-Witnesses and Victims. Victor Gollancz Ltd, London., 1934 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Mosley Fascism: The Man, His Policy & Methods. Labor Research Department, London., 1935 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Printers and the Fascist Menace: An Appeal to All Workers in the Trade. Printing & Allied Trades Anti-Fascist Movement, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Pritt, D.N. The Mosley Case. Labour Monthly, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Trade Union Policy in the War against Fascism. The Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1942 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Who Backs Mosley? Fascist Promise and Fascist Performance. Labour Research Department, London., 1934 (Box 43, Folder 2)
- Great Britain: Food Housing (10 pamphlets) (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Cornforth, Maurice. Food and Farming for Victory. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Milk. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - No More Depressed Areas. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Rust, William. Houses for the Millions. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Rose. Why We Pay More. Communist Party of Great Britain, London. (2 copies), undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Tenant Versus Landlord. London District Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - The Communist Party's Memorandum on Agriculture. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1942 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - The Future of Rent Control. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - The Great "Scales of Diet" Scandal. Workers Bookshop, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
- Great Britain: Labor and Industry I (15 pamphlets) (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Coal Combines in Yorkshire. The Labour Research Department, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Coward, Jack. We Want 40: The Case for the Seamen. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Fox, W. Imperial Chemical Industries Ltd. Martin Lawrence, London., 1934 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Horner, Arthur. Trade Unions and Unity. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Jefferys, J.B. Trade Unions in a Labour Britain. Fabian Publications, London., 1947 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Lambert, Miss F. Labour's Case for the Forty Hour Working Week... Marx Memorial Library and Workers' School, London., 1945 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Reorganization of the Electricity Supply Industry. The Labour Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Roberts, Ben. Trade Unions in the New Era. International Publishing Company, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - The Defence of the Seven Busmen. W.Payne, London., 1937 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - The Labour Movement in Britain. The Communist Party, London., 1949 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - The Story of the Steel Strike of 1945. Illawarra Trades & Labor Council & Newcastle Trades Hall Council., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - The Workers United Front: A Challenge to the Ruling Class. National Congress & March Council, London., 1933 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - What is Rationalisation? National Minority Movement, London., 1928 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - What is the Transport T.U.I? W.F.T.U. Publications Ltd, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - What's Wrong in the Textile Industry? An Analysis of the present state of the Industry and of the Unions. National Minority Movement, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
- Great Britain: Labor and Industry II (19 pamphlets) (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Aylward, Bert and Pat Coleman. London Docks. London District Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Bell, Tom. The Movement for World Trade Union. Daily Worker Publishing Company, Chicago, IL., 1925 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Clear the Lines: Better conditions, Better service. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Coal: A Policy. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Defend Trade Union Rights: A Communist Call to every Trade Unionist. The Communist Party, London., 1949 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Full Steam Ahead: A Programme for Railwaymen. The Communist Party, London., 1948 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Horner, Arthur. The Communist Party and the Coal Crisis. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Lewis, W. Arthur. Monopoly in British Industry. Fabian Publications, London., 1945 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - New Deal for Transport: What nationalism means to the workers in all branches of the transport industry. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Petch Arthur W. Trade Unionism: What Every Worker Should Know. National Council of Labour Colleges, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Ramelson, Bert. Incomes Policy: The Great Wage Freeze Trick. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - September 9th: "Drowned in a Sea of Working Class Activity." Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - The Future of Ship Building. The Communist Party, London., 1948 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - The Future of the Boot & Shoe Industry. The Communist Party, London., 1945 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - The London Bus Strike: What Next? London District Committee of the Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - The War on Wages. Labour Research Department, London., 1939 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - The World Revolution and the tasks of the British Working Class. Workers' International League, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Towards a greater Trade Union Movement: An analysis and suggestions of rimproved trade union structure, activity and unity. Communist Party, London., 1944 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Trade Unions Forward. The Marston Printing Co, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
- Great Britain: Labour Party (14 pamphlets) (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Bolsover, Philip. Corruption: Comments on the Lynskey Tribunal. The Communist Party, London., 1949 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - C.B. The Reds and the General Strike: The Lessons of the First General Strike of the British Working Class. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Kerrigan, Peter. Wages and Income Tax. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Labour Monthly. Proprietors, The Trinity Trust, London., 1946 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Gollan, John. Why Not Nationalise? Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Pollitt, Harry, J.R. Campbell, and R.P. Dutt. Welfare State or Warfare State? People's Press Printing Society, London., 1950 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Ridley, F.A. Towards The British Revolution. Independent Labour Party, London., 1943 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Smashing the Unemployed! Labour Party, London., 1932 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Stevens, W.C. Wages, Prices, and Profits. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Suthers, R.B. Simple Simon- The Socialist Scoundrel. Labour Party, London., 1932 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - The People's Savings. The Labour Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - The Reds and the Labour Party: Towards a Left-Wing Policy. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., 1926 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - The Unity Campaign. National Unity Campaign Committee, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Which Way for Labour? A Communist Perspective for the Labour Movement. Communist Campaign, London., 1986 (Box 43, Folder 6)
- Great Britain: Media (2 pamphlets) (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - The BBC. The Communist Party, London., 1945 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - The Great Film Lock-Out. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
- Great Britain: Peace (14 pamphlets) (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - A Hell of a Business. Communist Party, London., 1935 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Campbell, J.R. Over to Peace: Communist Policy for the Reconvention of Industry. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Chater, Tony. The Case for Peace and Disarmament. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Cole, G.D.H. Weakness Through Strength: The Economics of Disarmament. The Union of Democratic Control, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Cole, G.D.H. When the Fighting Stops. National Peace Council, London., 1943 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Jenkins, Clive. J ets and Jobs: Disarmament and the Workers. The Union of Democratic Control, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Lippay, Z. Behind the Scenes of the "Disarmament" Conference. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Our First Duty- Peace: A Statement of Policy on the Problems of Today. The Labour Party, London., 1951 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Peace to the World. The British Peace Committee, London., undated (Box 43, Drawer 8)
  - Schaffer, Gordon. German Rearmament Leads to War. British Peace Committee, London., 1951 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Snook, J. To Hell With War. National Command, Labour League of Ex-Servicemen, London., undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - The Communists were Right! The Communist Party, London., 1946 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - The Old World and the New Society: A Report on the Problems of War and Peace Reconstruction. The Labour Party, London., 1941 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - The People Want Peace. People's Press Printing Society, London., 1948 (Box 43, Folder 8)
- Great Britain: Socialism (19 pamphlets) (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Arnot, R. Page. Slavery or Socialism: Forward to the National Congress of Action. Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Bellamy, Edward. The Parable of the Water Tank. I.L.P. Guild of Youth and Young Labour Library, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Benjamin, Lawrence. The Position of the Middle-Class Worker in the Transition to Socialism. The Labour Party, London., 1935 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Burns, John. Municipal Socialism., 1902 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Campbell, J.R. A Socialist Solution to the Crisis. The Communist Party, London. (2 copies), 1948 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Cole, G.D.H. The Essentials of Socialisation. The New Fabian Research Bureau, London., 1931 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Doyle, Charlie. The British Road to Socialism Draft: Revolutionary Path or Diversion? Cassidy Publications, London., 1977 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Gollan, John. Which Road? The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Gollan, John. Which Way to Socialism? The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Jackson, T.A. Socialism: What? Why? How? The Communist Party, London., 1945 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Mahon, John. The Party of Socialism. Communist Party, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Robson, R. W. Why we talk Politics. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Socialism and the Condition of the People. The Labour Party, London., 1934 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Socialism and the Empire: Report of the I.L.P. Empire Policy Committee submitted to the Annual Conference of the Party. Independent Labour Party, London., 1926 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The British Road to Socialism: New text prepared by the Executive Committee as instructed by the 25th Party Congress. The Communist Party, London., 1957 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The British Road to Socialism: Programme adopted by the Executive Committee of the Communist Party. The Communist Party, London., 1951 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The British Road to Socialism. The Communist Party, London., 1968 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The British Road to Socialism. The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - The Transition to Socialism: A 3-Lesson Syllabus. The Communist Party, London., 1948 (Box 44, Folder 1)
- Great Britain: Unemployment (3 pamphlets) (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - 50,000,000 Unemployed: 150,000,000 Starving. Workers' Library Publishers, New York, NY., undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Hannington, Wal. Work for Ages: Not Slave Camps. National Unemployed Workers' Movement, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Piatnitsky, O. Unemployment and the Tasks of the Communists. Workers Library Publishers, New York, NY., 1931 (Box 44, Folder 2)
- Great Britain: U.S.S.R. (2 pamphlets) (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Coates, W.P. Why Russia should be Recognised. The National "Hands Off Russia" Committee, London., 1924 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Soviet-American Relations. "Soviet News," London., 1948 (Box 44, Folder 3)
- Great Britain: Women (6 pamphlets) (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - 50 Facts about British Women at War. British Information Services, New York, NY., 1943 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Brown, Isabel. Women & the War. The Communist Party of Great Britain, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Wauters, Arthur. Eve in Overalls. British Information Service, New York, NY., undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Woman's Place? The Communist Party, London., undated (Box 44, Folder 4)